Once the two panes are showing up on a tablet, let's
modify our code to handle the list item click. On the phone,
if an item is clicked in the forecast fragment, then we
must launch the detail activity. On the tablet UI, once an item
in the forecast fragment is clicked, we notify the main activity,
which goes and replaces the detail fragment. The reason the two fragments
don't talk to each other is because we want to maintain abstraction from
each other. If the forecast list fragment started assuming that the detail
fragment was always right next to it, then the assumption would break.
For example, on the phone where the detail fragment is not inside
the main activity. Therefore our fragment must go through its activity and
the activity must know how to dispatch the event to the other
fragments. Keep in mind that our fragment doesn't always have to be
used in the same activity, in order for the forecast fragment to
talk to the main activity we should create a callback interface. It's
a better assumption to say that the fragment will always be within
an activity that implements this callback than to say that
the forecast fragment will always be inside the main activity. The
detail fragment is a good example of how a fragment can
be used in two different activities. The main activity and the
detail activity. So don't rely on get activity returning a
specific activity class. Using the gist that we provided, use a
callback class to notify the activity that a list item has
been selected. See the hint below on the item click listener.
Then the activity can either launch the detail activity or
replace the detail fragment, based on whether it's a phone or
tablet. When you work on this task, you'll run into
an issue of how to pass the selected date to the
detail fragment. Now your instinct might say to create a
custom constructor where you can pass in the date. However, we
don't normally create custom fragment constructors. If you ever rotate the
device, for example, the system can't call your custom fragment constructor
with the right parameters, however it can use the
empty fragment constructor and initialize it with the same bundle
of arguments you used earlier. So to pass information to
initialize a fragment, create a bundle of key value pairs,
and then set that as the arguments on the
fragment. Don't confuse this arguments
bundle with the savedInstanceState bundle.
Once a fragment has been initialized, you can't change the
arguments. You can only read from them, as seen here.
On the other hand the saved state bundle is for storing information
once a fragment has been running. And you can populate it in
the on savedInstanceState method. The bundle
can preserve state across orientation changes
or if the fragment or activity gets killed by the system. That's why
you receive it back again in the onCreate or onCreateView methods. This
is what the app should look like when you're done. When you
tap on a different date, it updates the detail pane. You can
remove any hard coded data because
the layout should be populated dynamically now.